Guide to the Red Bale / Percy Arthur Rice Institute football memorabilia collection, 1925-2008 UA 224
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Red Bale / Percy Arthur Rice Institute football memorabilia collection
1925-2008
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Arthur, Percy; Bale, Allen "Red"
UA 224
4 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
This collection consists of Rice Institute football scrapbooks, correspondence, team photographs, and sports memorabilia.
Biographical Sketch
Percy Arthur was Captain of the 1934 Rice Institute football team and participated in the Rice Owls first Southwestern Conference championship in 1934. Previously Arthur had been captain of the 1929 Reagan High School football team. Following graduation from Rice, he attended Columbia University, receiving a master's degree in education and in 1936 returned to Rice as assistant football coach. Later he became South Texas Agency manager for the Southland Life Insurance Company. He married Ivy Arthur Bale in 1940.
Allen "Red" Bale was Percy Arthur's football teammate and college roommate. He coached at Rice University and became an athletic director there. He married Ivy Arthur Bale, Percy Arthur's widow, in 2000.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of Rice Institute football scrapbooks, correspondence, team photographs, and sports memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Received from "Froggy" Williams October 2009.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; College sports; Football; Rice University -- History; Sports
Document Types
photographs; awards; memorabilia
- Series I: Photographs, speeches and scrapbooks, 123826
  - Photograph - team action shot, 123829 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Portrait - Percy Arthur, 124130 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1934 Rice Owls/Percy Arthur Scrapbook, 123830 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Percy Arthur Scrapbook, 123831 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Speech Re: Percy Arthur, 123832 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Re: Saturday's Children, 1971-1973; 123833 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 123834 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1935 "R" Banquet, 123835 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Binder of notes to Red Bale from former Rice football players, 123836 (Box 1, Folder -)
- Series II: Awards and trophies, 123827
  - MVP Trophy from Forest Ave High School awarded to Red Bale, 1930; 123837 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 50th Reunion 1953-2003, SWC-Cotton Bowl Football Champions, 123838 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - SWC Football Co-Champions Medal, 1994; 123839 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - A. M. "Red" Bale, Rice All-Time SWC Team Medal, 1995; 123840 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - Career Service Award to Coach Red Bale for 66 Years of Service to Rice, 1932-1998; 123841 (Box 2, Folder -)
- Series III: Oversize photographs and scrapbooks, 123828
  - Rice Football Banquet poster, 1938; 123842 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Framed Photo: Honored for Selection on Pre-War All Time Rice Team, 1995; 123843 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Framed Photo: Pre-War and Post-War All Time Rice Teams at the last Southwest Conference Game, 1995; 123844 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Framed Photo: Southwest Conference Champion Teams, 1934-1957; 123845 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Distinguished "R" Award awarded to Red Bale, 123846 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - High School and College Football scrapbook by Red Bale, 1934-1936; 123847 (Box 4, Folder -)